Guide to the Samuel H. Gardiner papers, 1839-1864 MS 038
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Samuel H. Gardiner papers
1839-1864
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Gardiner, Samuel H.
MS 038
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection consists of 193 letters written to a Long Island attorney, Samuel H. Gardiner, Esq. of Sag Harbor and New York City. The letters give a good picture of the activities of a counselor at law of that period. The majority of the letters concern legal matters; however, some relate to politics, touching on the election campaigns of 1844 and 1848.
Biographical Note
Samuel H. Gardiner was an attorney based in Sag Harbor and New York City.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 193 letters written to a Long Island attorney, Samuel H. Gardiner, Esq. of Sag Harbor and New York City. The letters give a good picture of the activities of a counselor at law of that period. The majority of the letters concern legal matters; however, some relate to politics, touching on the election campaigns of 1844 and 1848.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Edward H. Phillips on March 15, 1960.
Index Terms
Subjects
Law and legislation; Lawyers; Politics and government
Document Types
letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Correspondence, 1839-1864, 255274
  - 1839, 255290 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1840, 255289 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1841, 255288 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1842, 255287 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1843, 255286 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1844, 255285 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1845, 255284 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1846, 255283 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1847, 255282 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1848, 255281 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1849, 255280 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1850, 255279 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1851, 255278 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1852, 255277 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1854-1864, 255276 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Undated correspondence, 255275 (Box 1, Folder 16)